Guide to the Frank Richard Oastler Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Lantern Slides, 1908-1938; Series II; 71' (167 boxes)
  - UNCLASSIFIED LANTERN SLIDES
    - Other Lantern Slides
      - Isle Royale National Park (5), 1934, undated (Box 230, Folder 253)
      - Isle Royale National Park (6), 1934, undated (Box 230, Folder 254)
      - Isle Royale National Park (5), 1926, 1934 (Box 230, Folder 255)
      - Mt. McKinley, Muldrow Glacier, Alaska (8) (Box 230, Folder 256)
      - Mt. McKinley & Region. Kenai Peninsula, Alaska. Cassiar Mts., B.C. (9), 1927, 1935 (Box 231, Folder 257)
      - Mt. Rainier (6), 1924-1931, undated (Box 231, Folder 258)
      - Mt. Rainier (7), 1930-1931, undated (Box 231, Folder 259)
      - Westchester Fall (6), 1919-1924 (Box 231, Folder 260)
      - Westchester Fall (6), 1919-1926 (Box 231, Folder 261)
      - Westchester Fall (6), 1918-1933 (Box 231, Folder 262)
      - Westchester Spring (6), 1925-1926 (Box 231, Folder 263)
      - Westchester Spring (6), 1925-1926, undated (Box 231, Folder 264)
      - Westchester Summer (9), 1911-1934, undated (Box 231, Folder 265)
      - White Canyon & Bridges on way to Colorado River (6), 1925 (Box 231, Folder 266)
      - Yellowstone National Park (6), undated (Box 231, Folder 267)
      - Yellowstone National Park (6), 1925-1934, undated (Box 231, Folder 268)
      - Flowers (5), undated (Box 232, Folder 269)
      - Flowers (5), undated (Box 232, Folder 270)
      - Unidentified black and white flowers (8) (Box 232, Folder 271)
      - Unidentified black and white flowers (7) (Box 232, Folder 272)
      - Flowers, place unknown (6), undated (Box 232, Folder 273)
      - Egrets, Doe and Miscellaneous scenes (7) (Box 232, Folder 274)
      - Prairie Dogs (8), undated (Box 232, Folder 275)
      - Unidentified Black and White Eggs -- Animals (3), undated (Box 232, Folder 276)
      - Miscellaneous slides (13), 1932, undated (Box 232, Folder 277)
      - Alaska Lecture. 221 slides in box, numbered in order of presentation, 1927, undated (Box 233, Folder 278)
        With tag reading "Lecture given by Dr. Oastler just as he gave it." Numbers 1-17, 19-54, 56-80, 82-89, 91-225. Holograph notes are inserted for 18, 55, 81, 90 indicating that they had to be redone
      - Canadian Rockies Lecture. 139 slides in box, numbered in order of presentation, 1925-1933, undated (Box 234, Folder 279)
        With tag labeled "Canadian Rockies. Lecture given by Dr. Oastler just as he gave it. Shadow Lake, Haiduk Lake, Mt. Ball." Holograph note inside states that there are 155 slides in box; numbers currently present: 2-4, 4-13, 15-33, 35-79, 81, 81-140
      - Isle Royale National Park, Michigan. 190 slides in box, numbered in order of presentation, 1920-1933, undated (Box 235, Folder 280)
        With tag labeled "Lecture given by Dr. Oastler just as he gave it. Beaver slides, Rome, Westchester, Maine Flowers." Holograph note inside states that there are 187 slides in box; numbers currently present: 1-106, 108-124, 126-192. There are notes for 107 and 125 indicating that they had to be redone
      - Alaska, Canadian Rockies, and unidentified. 120 slides, all but two black and white, 1927-1933, undated (Box 236, Folder 281)
- Photographic Negatives, 1912-1935, undated; Series III; 0.20' (1 box)
  Series III, Photographic Negatives, is organized into two subseries: Glass Plate Negatives and Cut Film Negatives.
  - GLASS PLATE NEGATIVES
    - Arizona: Altar, Snake kiwa; Kiva, Oraibi; Snake dance, Oraibi; Snakes, kiva; Tucson animals; Tucson flowers, undated (Box 237, Folder 282)
      Image of Snakes, kiva by James Photo
    - California: Desert Primroses near Palm Springs, Santa Barbara flowers, 1920, undated (Box 237, Folder 283)
      Desert Primroses image signed Willard
    - Canadian Rockies: Two rams, Athabasca, undated (Box 237, Folder 284)
    - Olympic Region: Elk (Box 237, Folder 285)
    - Wyoming: Bears, Crow, Deer in Yellowstone, Elk, Mountain lion, Mountain sheep, undated (Box 237, Folder 286)
    - Place unidentified: Deer swimming Lake [?], Elk, Mountain lion, Mountain sheep, Sea gulls, Unidentified, undated (Box 237, Folder 287)
    - Empty folder numbers (Box 237, Folder 288-293)
  - CUT FILM NEGATIVES
    - Cut Film Negatives
      There are approximately eight boxes of cut film nitrate negatives which are restricted. They are presumed to be of photographs in the photograph albums in Series I. For further information, contact the appropriate curator.
      Conditions Governing Access
      Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
    - Envelopes, 1912-1935; 13 (Box 253)
      Empty envelopes formerly housing cut film nitrate negatives. Many are annotated with locations and dates. A few contain one or two prints.
- Film Surrogates, Series IV
  Four copies of films made by Frank Richard Oastler that record undated trips to Glacier National Park and to Yellowstone National Park, a trip down the Colorado River in 1925, and a trip to Alaska in 1927. The original films were badly deteriorated and the Beinecke Library pursued extensive conservation of these four prior to the transfer of the films to the Library of Congress.
  Separated Materials
  These four films were among the 204 black and white 16mm motion picture films documenting the Oastlers' Western trips and visits to other national parks that were transferred to Library of Congress, Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, National Audio-Visual Conservation Center in 2012.
  - Digitally reformatted film surrogates
    - Yellowstone National Park: Beaver (Reel 49)
    - Glacier National Park, Montana (Reel 80)
    - Caribou, Bear, Alaska, 1927 (Reel 91)
    - Colorado River Trip, 1925 (unnumbered reel)
  - Analog film preservation copies
    Boxes 241-252: Restricted Fragile Material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
- Oversize, 1915, undated; 0.1' (1 box) and 3 broadside folders
  Broadside folders 294-295a, Oversize, contains material from Series I and II, arranged in box order.
  - Printed maps previously in the "Maps" envelope at the front of the 1914 Mount Robson Trip, Album I (in series I) (Box bsd, folder 294)
  - Printed map previously stored at back of 1917 New Mexico Album I (in series I) (Box bsd, folder 295)
  - Oastler Collection sign (in series II), undated (Box bsd, folder 295a)
  - "Uncle Ned," Bull Moose, Rock Harbor, Isle Royale National Park, Michigan (in series I), undated (Box 240 (Oversize), Folder 295b)
  - "Uncle Ned," Bull Moose, Rock Harbor, Isle Royale National Park, Michigan (Box 240 (Oversize), Folder 295c)
  - Squirrel, probably in Isle Royale National Park, Michigan (Box 240 (Oversize), Folder 295d)
  - White Birches, Isle Royale National Park, Michigan (Box 240 (Oversize), Folder 295e)
  - Frog being fed a dragonfly by Mrs. Oastler at Mud Lake, Isle Royale National Park, Michigan (Box 240 (Oversize), Folder 295f)
  - Two moose, probably in Isle Royale National Park, Michigan (Box 240 (Oversize), Folder 295g)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.80' (2 boxes)
  Boxes 238-239, Restricted Fragile Papers, contain fragile originals. The material is arranged in folder order and may only be seen with the permission of the appropriate curator.
  - Box 52, folder 52 (Box 238, Folder 296)
  - Box 237, folders 282-287 (Box 239, Folder 297)